americanblinds.com 2009-09-03

# American Blinds Wallpaper and More : Resource Center: American Blinds Wallpaper and More

**Privacy and Security** This privacy policy is for American Blinds, Wallpaper & More. Our homepage on the Web is located at[ www.americanblinds.com](http://www.americanblinds.com/default.asp). The full text of our privacy policy is stated below. Users may go to [our registration section](https://www.americanblinds.com/register/default.asp) to opt-in or opt-out of use of their information. We invite you to contact us if you have questions about this policy. You may contact us by mail at the following address: 

**American Blinds, Wallpaper & More  
Att: E-Commerce Dept.  
31557 Schoolcraft Rd.  
Livonia, MI 48150-1847  
USA  
**  
You may contact us by e-mail by [clicking here](https://www.americanblinds.com/customer/email_request.asp?msgid=6). 

You may call us at **1- 800- 509- 8222**

**Dispute Resolution**  
Privacy/Security Dispute: If you have a question regarding our privacy policy or wish to dispute a privacy related issue, please contact our Customer Service department at 1-800-575-9019. **

Additional Information

**  
This policy is valid until 31 January 2010 at 12:00:00 EST.

**Data Collection**  
P3P stands for “The Platform for Privacy Policies”, documentation which is maintained at the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C). P3P policies declare the data they collect in groups (also referred to as "statements"). This policy contains one data group. The data practices of this group are explained below. 

Group: American Blinds, Wallpaper & More

We collect the following information:

Click-stream data  
HTTP cookies  
Search terms  
Transaction history  
User's Name  
Home mailing address  
Home e-mail address  
Unique identifiers  
Computer information  
Interactive data

At the user's option, we may also collect the following data:

Name Prefix  
User's Birth Date  
Home telephone numbers  
Home fax number

This data will be used for the following purposes:

Completion and support of the current activity  
Web site and system administration  
Research and development  
One-time tailoring. The user is allowed to opt-out of this usage  
Anonymous user analysis  
Anonymous user profiling and decision-making  
Contacting visitors for marketing of services or products  
This data will be used by our agents and ourselves

In addition, the following types of entities will receive this information:

Delivery services.  
Others following the same practices. The user must opt-in to this data sharing.  
Unrelated third parties. The user must opt-in to this data sharing.

The following explanation is provided for why this data is collected:

When you place an order or register on our site, we require you to provide your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, and credit card information (when ordering products only). We may also require you to create a username and password. This allows us to keep a user profile so that we may customize preferences for each user, as well as provide a more efficient method for users to submit information to americanblinds.com when placing an order or a request for product information. When you order a product and/or register, we also give you the option of submitting personal information such as your phone number, gender, date of birth, and/or other information. This allows us to know you better and possibly tailor any specific features, promotions, or other notifications to you. When registering with our site, you are also given a choice whether you would like to be on our mailing list, or whether you would prefer to opt-out and not receive such mailings. When you enter a contest or other promotional feature at our site, we may again ask for your name, address, username and password so that we are able to better administer the contest and notify winners.

**Information Sharing**

We utilize third-party companies to perform certain functions for us. Examples include order fulfillment, package delivery, the sending of emails and direct mail, data analysis, marketing optimization programs, credit card processing, etc. These third parties are given only the data that they need to perform the function that they are engaged in, and are not allowed to use it for any other purpose. We may be required to disclose your personal information to third parties to comply with applicable laws, subpoenas, or court orders. 

We do make our customer postal mailing list available to other reputable organizations from time to time. You may opt out of this process by going to [our registration section](https://www.americanblinds.com/register/default.asp). 

In the event of a merger or acquisition, your information may be transferred to the successor entity.  

**Cookies**  
Cookies are a technology that can be used to provide you with tailored information from a Web site. A cookie is an element of data that a Web site can send to your browser, which may then store it on your system. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it.  
Our site makes use of cookies. Cookies are used for the following purposes:

Site administration  
Contacting users  
Completing the user's current activity  
User targeting  
Pseudonymous analysis  
Pseudonym-based decision-making  
Research and development   

**Security Practices**  
We have appropriate physical, electronic and procedural security safeguards in place to protect and secure the information we collect.

In addition, our web site uses Secure Sockets Layering (SSL) to encrypt your personal credit information, including your credit card number, before it travels over the Internet. SSL is the industry standard for secure online transactions. By using SSL, we make placing an order online at our web site just as safe as giving your credit card number over the phone  

**Safe Shopping Guarantee**  
We guarantee that every transaction you make at americanblinds.com will be safe and secure. In the unlikely event that unauthorized charges are made to your card as a result of shopping at americanblinds.com, you'll pay nothing.

Under the Fair Credit Billing Act, your bank account cannot hold you liable for more than $50.00 of fraudulent charges. If your bank does hold you liable for any of this $50.00, americanblinds.com will cover the entire liability, up to the full $50.00. americanblinds.com will cover this liability only if the unauthorized use of your credit card resulted through no fault of your own from purchases made at americanblinds.com while using our secure server. 

In the event of unauthorized use of your credit card, you must notify your credit card provider in accordance with its reporting rules and procedures. Any material changes to the privacy policy will be posted on the web site and communicated via e-mail.
